# Luong-Ha Nguyen

Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning Engineer

Experienced AI/ML Engineer with a background in developing and optimizing learning paradigms as well as AI/ML pipelines, including modeling, validation, and deployment strategies in production. Skilled in uncertainty modeling and machine learning approaches, with a notable track record in driving innovation in manufacturing, renewable energy, infrastructure monitoring, and aerospace sectors through interdisciplinary teamwork.

( hazone.me

github.com/lhnguyen102

in linkedin.com/in/luong-ha-nguyen-697941b4

♦ +1 (438) 928-2616
☑ luongha.nguyen@gmail.com
♠ Montreal, QC, <u>CANADA</u>

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Machine Learning Engineer at AI Redefined | Montreal, QC, CA

July, 2022 - present

- Develop end-to-end machine learning pipelines for time series forecasting and anomaly detection, using reinforcement learning with human feedback to continually enhance accuracy through insights from operators and asset managers.
- Lead the development of vision-based detection algorithms using reinforcement learning with human feedback.
- Spearhead research initiatives with both industrial and academic partners.

## Applied Research Associate at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

May, 2022 - present

- Lead and coordinate a team of PhDs and postdocs in the collaborative development of an efficient learning paradigm for deep neural networks to enhance accuracy and reduce training time across various learning tasks.
- Lead the technical development of open-source software cuTAGI.
- Lead the technical development of Python interface for integration with the C++/CUDA backend.

#### Machine Learning Engineer at Shearwater Aerospace | Montreal, QC, CA

September, 2021 - June, 2022

- Developed machine learning-based path planning system to improve UAV flight efficiency.
- Developed an autonomous control system using reinforcement learning for UAVs.

Postdoctoral Researcher at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

November, 2019 - September, 2021

- Formulated a theoretical approach for modeling uncertainty in deep neural networks.
- Implemented and tested the proposed approach on supervised, unsupervised, and reinforcement learning tasks.

#### **SKILLS**



Languages Fluent in English and French, with native proficiency in Vietnamese

### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Computer Science for Civil Engineering at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

October, 2019

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

cuTAGI for Bayesian Neural Networks (2018-present) | https://tagiml.com

- cuTAGI: An open-source Bayesian neural network developed in C++/CUDA. It quantifies uncertainty in deep neural networks for various learning tasks, enhancing output reliability and accuracy.

Transformer Temporal Fusion (2023) | Source code: https://github.com/lhnguyen102/tft-sgd

- Implementation of the Transformer Temporal Fusion (TFT) method, leveraging self-attention mechanisms for enhanced accuracy and detailed explainability in time series forecasting.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Analytically Tractable Hidden-States Inference in Bayesian Neural Networks. JMLR, 2022.
- 2. Tractable Approximate Gaussian Inference for Bayesian Neural Networks. JMLR, 2021.
- 3. Analytically Tractable Inference in Neural Networks-An Alternative to Backpropagation, NeurIPS, 2021.